Today we’ll talk about everybody’s favorite topic, death.
今天我们会谈及大家最爱的话题：死亡
You probably expect to live up to your life expectancy, right?
你可能会预计  你能活到比自己的预期寿命更长  对吗
No wrong. You’ll probably live longer than that.
没错  你很有可能活得更久
This graph shows the probability of death at a certain age.
这张柱状图显示了在某个年龄段死亡的概率
The red line here is the mean value, that’s the average age of death
这里的红线是死亡年龄的平均值
and what’s normally called life expectancy.
一般称之为“预期寿命”
In first world countries it’s typically early 80s.
在老牌发达国家  预期寿命一般略高于80岁
Though the age at which most people die is higher, that’s the median.
但更多人的死亡岁数要比均值更大  这也是中位数
But unless you’re a newborn,
不过  只要你不是刚出生
the mean value of the entire graph isn’t relevant for you.
整个图表的平均值就跟你无关
If you survived the first year of your life,
如果你活到满一周岁了
you’d instead take the mean of the remaining years which is at somewhat higher age.
你应当只用剩余的（也就是更大的）年龄来计算平均值
Now we repeat this for all further ages.
你不断长大变老时也重复这样的计算
As you see, the older you get,
如你所见 你的年龄越大
the further the mean of the remaining years moves higher ages.
剩余年龄的平均值就会越靠右
This leads to the odd conclusion that
这就会导致一个奇怪的结论：
if you’ve reached the age of your life expectancy
你如果达到了预期寿命
you can actually expect to live another 8-10 years.
反而可以估计  自己还能再活个十年八年